Chu Meng
楚蒙
Call the eldest son
ボスを呼んで来い
Father, why did you urgently summon me?
父上急に私を呼ばれたのは何の御用でしょうか
Come
来る
My body
私の体
Is getting worse day by day
日ごとに悪くなっている
Father, what are you saying?
父上何を言っているのですか
Do you remember
覚えていますか
When I fought back to the capital
あの年父は京城に戻って戦った
The first time you called me father
あなたが初めてパパと呼んだ時
What did I promise you?
父さんはあなたに何か約束しましたか
I said
父さんが言っていた
To make you the king of the entire realm
あなたに全世界の王になってほしい
This, take it
これを持って
Father, this
お父様これ
Rise
起きる
You've managed court affairs for many years
あなたは長年朝廷の事務を治めています
I'll entrust Xuan Kingdom to you
父は宣国をあなたに託します
I'm at ease
お父さん安心して
Your mother
あなたの母
Can also rest in peace
安心できる
But
しかし
I have one thing
父さん一つお願いがあります
I need your promise
お父さんはあなたの約束を聞きたい
If Father commands
父上のご命令です
Your son will obey
子は従わないことがない
Your second brother is impulsive
あなたの二番目の弟は向こう見ずです
But
しかし
He values family and state
彼は家族と国を重んじる
Values loyalty and righteousness
情に厚く義理堅い
Now in the army
今軍の中で
Grand General Zu Yue is in command
祖月大将軍が駐屯している
The Second Prince is not your enemy
二番目の彼はあなたの敵ではありません
He is your support, understand?
あなたの助けですわかりましたか
In my lifetime
父の一生
I've done many things that can only be kept in my heart
心にしか隠せないことをたくさんしてきた
Loyal ministers and good generals, I've sacrificed
忠実な家臣優れた将軍父が犠牲になった
Brothers
義兄弟
I've also raised my sword against
父も刀を向けたことがある
Even though we drove out Wuzhao and recovered Great Xuan
たとえ烏伖を追放しても大志を復興する
Such things
こんなこと
How can merits and faults cancel each other out?
それがどうして功績と過ちを相殺できるのでしょうか
Father
父上
Sheng'er
盛児
I want all of this
父さんはこれらすべてを実現させたい
To end with me
すべては父に終結する
Our Sikong family
私たち司空家の人々
Must not shed Sikong blood again
もう司空家の血に染まらないでください
I want you to lead the people
私はあなたに民を率いるよう命じる
Into a golden age
盛世に入る
To be a perfect and wise ruler
欠点のない聡明な君主になる
Your son
私の子
Will not fail Father's trust
父皇の重い信頼を決して裏切らない
Rise
起きて
Good son
いい息子